SHAKER KATTOULA

FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER

SUMMARY

 Software Developer from San Diego with a strong passion for problem-solving and engineering creative solutions using code.
 Reflective communicator and collaborative team member. Backed with over 5+ years of professional customer service and operations management.

ACADEMIC BACKGROUND

California State University of San Marcos

BA IN PSYCHOLOGY, GRADUATED IN MAY 2019

- Was selected to be on the dean's list for an excellent GPA, 2015
- Participated in numerous research projects with groups both large and small, 2015-2019

SKILLS AND INTERESTS

Professional Skills

 Skilled in critical thinking, problem-solving, communication, team collaboration, adaptability and self-discipline

Technical Skills

- Proficient in: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, NodeJS/Express, MongoDB
- Frameworks/libraries: React Native, Bootstrap/Reactstrap, jQuery, AWS, Git Flow, Github, Mongoose
- Testing: Jest, Enzyme

CONTACT INFO

- Email: smkattoula@gmail.com
- Portfolio: shakerkattoula.com
- LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/shakerkattoula/
- Github: github.com/smkattoula

EXPERIENCE

Full Stack Software Developer Intern (Remote)
VICTORISE, CO. APRIL 2020 - JUNE 2020

- Used MERN stack to connect front-end/back-end technologies and improve existing web application UI features
- Created UX analysis bug reports for both web and mobile applications
- Improved functionality of UI features on mobile application using React Native
- Communicated effectively with the project manager on a daily basis to ensure timely completion of tasks and quality assurance
- · Utilized weekly sprint planning via Agile methodology

Full Stack Web Developer

LEARN ACADEMY. JANUARY 2020 - APRIL 2020

- Completed over 480 hours of hands-on coding experience in settings that include pair-programming, mob projects, and individual work as part of an intensive coding boot camp in San Diego
- Active participant in pair programming and demonstrated effective communication/collaborative skills
- Created full-stack applications using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, Ruby, Ruby on Rails, and SQL

Store Operations Manager

MINUTE SHOP LIQUOR AND DELI, MAY 2016 - MARCH 2020

- Operated the store very efficiently with zero supervision while ensuring that only the highest standards are met.
- Managed 5 different employees and was responsible for coordinating each person's schedule
- Maintained appropriate levels of inventory throughout the business and ensured proper pricing
- Upheld a professional work attitude at all times even while handling the most difficult customers